Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太と➡
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
ひびと
栄光の日生まれの弟･日々人＞
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
＜日本人初のムーン･ウォーカーと
なった日々人は 月面での➡
A lunar accident has left Hibito struggling on the sidelines, suffering from a panic disorder.
事故の影響でパニック障害と
なったものの➡
復帰試験に何とか合格した＞
But he's able to pass a test to return to active duty.
＜一方 日々人のはるか後ろから
月を目指し始めた 兄･六太は➡
Older brother Mutta continues his long quest to the moon,
ついに 月のミッションの
バックアップクルーに任命され➡
having finally been selected as a
backup member for a lunar mission.
And he's about to begin training.
訓練を始める｡しかし
月へ一緒に行くメンバーは➡
However, his fellow crew members are a unique bunch.
ひと癖も ふた癖もある
連中ばかりだった＞
I can't get lost in what I'm doing, nothing works out
I don't want these endlessly dull days
I hope I can move on
before the call of freedom drags me away
What's your wish?
I just want some real courage
We all stare doubt in the face, every one of us
Isn't the unpredictability of life the fun of it?
Devote your life to that dream you can't express
Let's go, advance against the wind, our road is long
Embrace the pain of it too
Take a big breath now, and yell
Big Bang! Chase it without fear!
I want to dream so badly it amazes me
There's cowardice in the way of your true wish
Rip that hot veil aside
#93 In the Corner of My Heart
Unfortunately,
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)残念ながら 本心から
彼らと共に➡
no one wants to go to space with them.
宇宙へ行きたがる者は いません｡
考え抜いた結果が➡
That's why we ended up putting them together.
半ば やけっぱちの
この組み合わせです｡➡
どうしようもない 孤独な彼らを
一緒のチームにさせ➡
We assigned the lonely astronauts to the same team,
そこに ナンバ･ムッタという男を
放り込む｡➡
and then we added Nanba Mutta.
そして あともう１人｡➡
And with one more person,
このクルーの
キャプテンが決まれば➡
the captain of the crew,
何とかなるかも しれません｡
it just might work.
(役員)あては あるんですか？
Do you know who you'll turn to?
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ええ メールでは
一度断られましたが １人｡
Yes.
When I sent an e-mail, I was turned down...
But I have a candidate.
この会議の後 彼に直接会って
話してみます｡
After this meeting, I plan to see him in person.
さて 皆さん揃いましたね｡
Well, it looks like everyone's here.
では 始めてもらいましょう｡
Then let's get started.
(ﾓﾘｿﾝ)はい 天文チーム代表
ダニエル･モリソンです｡
Yes.
I am Daniel Morrison, representing the astronomy team.
ナサ
我々が ＮＡＳＡとの
共同開発を切望する➡
We have brought a new proposal for the joint development, alongside NASA, of a lunar telescope.
月面望遠鏡の新案を
用意してまいりました｡
では よろしくお願いします｡
We hope you like it.
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)ありがとう ヒビト
案内してくれて｡
Thank you for bringing me, Hibito.
なんば
(南波 日々人)いいんだよ｡
It was nothing.
《あれが ＡＬＳの天文学者…》
That's the astronomer with ALS...
え～ 以前 我々が提案した 月面
望遠鏡を月で作るという案は➡
Our original proposal to build a telescope on the moon was rejected due to a number of issues.
数々の問題点を指摘され
却下となりました｡➡
完成するまで 長期に渡り 多数の
宇宙飛行士の手が必要になる｡➡
The construction would have been performed by many astronauts, over a long time.
作業しづらい月面で作ったものは
予定通りの精度に➡
Given how difficult it is to move around on the moon, construction would not be as precise as planned.
満たない恐れがある｡
大きな鏡は デブリ被害にあう➡
The large mirror ran a significant risk of being hit by debris.
リスクも高くなる｡その後の修理
メンテナンスが 毎回 大規模な➡
An extensive mission would be required for repairs and periodic maintenance,
ミッションになってしまい 結果
コストが莫大になってしまう等…｡
which would, in turn, increase costs.
ですが今回 シャロン博士が
考えた 新たな案は➡
However, Dr. Sharon has a new proposal that addresses all of those concerns.
そのすべてを クリアしています｡
手ごたえ ありなんじゃない？
ＮＡＳＡ側は みんな➡
I think it went well.
Everyone from NASA seemed happy with it.
あの案に 納得してた
様子だったし｡
そうね きっと上手くいくわよね｡
そう信じましょう｡
Yes.
I know this will work.
I have faith.
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)ヒビトは 最近どう？
How are you doing, Hibito?
ああ 俺はもう大丈夫だよ｡
いつでも戻れる｡
Oh, I'm fine now.
I can go back any time.
あとは どのミッションに
アサインされるのかを待つだけだ｡
I just have to wait to see which mission I'll be assigned to.
そう…よかったわ｡
Really... That's wonderful.
ありがとう ヒビト｡
ムッタによろしくね｡
Thank you, Hibito.
Say hello to Mutta for me.
残念がるだろうな
シャロンに会えなかったこと｡
He'll be upset that he didn't get to see you.
(ﾀﾘｰ)あれ？何これ
古いカメラだね～｡
Huh?
What's with the antique camera?
(南波 六太)あ…まず半押しして
ピント合わせて➡
Oh, while you're focusing, press the button halfway,
で パシャッと｡
動画モードに なってないよね？
then snap away.
It isn't in video mode, is it?
え～と 多分これで…｡➡
Let's see... That should do it.
はい撮るよ～｡
ヨロシクゥ！
Okay, here I go.
Go for it.
Yah, man!
(ﾍﾞﾃｨ)フン！どこの観光客よ
あんたら｡
Are you here for sightseeing?
この暑さで 脳みそ
とろけちゃってんじゃない？
Has the heat made you daft?
(ｶﾙﾛ)今２１度だよ ベティ｡
こんな適温が 暑いだなんて｡
It's only seventy degrees...
That isn't considered hot.
君は ホットな心の持ち主だけど
どうやら 体もホッ…｡
You have a heart that's hot, but I guess your body is just as—
Can you shut up?
ちょっと 黙ってくれないアンタ
蹴飛ばすわよ！
I'll kick your ass.
Yah, man!
《う～ん チクショー｡
でも まあいいや｡➡
Damn it...
Whatever.
この写真 シャロンに見せたら
喜ぶぞ～｡後で送ろう》
When I show her these pictures, Sharon will be thrilled!
I'll send them over later.
《なんたって 初めて着る
月面用の宇宙服だもんな》
Since this is the first time I've worn a lunar spacesuit...
《カッコいいぜ～！》
I look awesome!
(ﾍﾞﾃｨ)それにしても ダッサイわね
この宇宙服｡
These spacesuits are so lame.
デザイン 何とかなんないの？
Can't they improve the design?
(ﾀﾘｰ)ついてるよキミ！今
新しいの 開発中なんだ！
You're in luck! We're working on a new design right now!
(ﾍﾞﾃｨ)間に合うの？
(ﾀﾘｰ)多分 間に合うよ｡
You're gonna finish in time?
I think so, probably!
(ﾍﾞﾃｨ)早くしてよね｡
Hurry it up, then.
なるほど｡この案は
実に現実的ですな｡
I see... This proposal is very realistic.
前向きに検討しましょう｡
We'll give it serious consideration.
However, it will require a great deal of work.
(職員)しかし これはこれで
大変な仕事になりそうだ｡➡
天文学と この企画に
熱意を持てる➡
Are there any astronauts who would take interest in this project?
宇宙飛行士が いるのかどうか…｡
それなら…それなら 大丈夫です｡
That...
That shouldn't be a concern.
ナンバ…ムッタですか？
Nanba Mutta?
この月面望遠鏡は 我々
天文チームの夢であり➡
The lunar telescope is the astronomy team's dream.
私 個人の願いでもあります｡
この願いを 必ず叶えてくれると➡
It is also a wish of mine.
When he was a child, Mutta promised me that he would grant my wish.
まだ子供だったムッタは
約束してくれました｡
そして そのムッタは今
月に立つ準備をしています｡
And Mutta is currently training for the moon.
It...
こればっかりは 訓練教官達の
評価によるところが大きいので➡
It will depend on his instructors' review of his performance...
彼が アサインされるという
約束は できません｡
I can't guarantee that he'll be assigned to this mission.
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)ええ それで構いません｡
心の片隅に…｡
Yes, that's fine.
I'll keep it in the corner of my heart.
I understand.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)わかりました…
心の片隅に｡
The corner of my heart...
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)珍しいことも あるもんだ｡
室長が 自ら➡
This is unusual...
The chief paying a visit to an astronaut's office.
飛行士の部屋まで出向くとは｡➡
かつての室長には
いなかったタイプだな｡ハハッ…｡
None of your predecessors would have done this.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)あんた以外に
思いつかないんでな｡
You're the only person I could think of.
どうしようもない彼らを
まとめられそうなキャプテンは｡➡
The only captain who could control that group of misfits.
セス
ＣＥＳー６２のサブクルーに
加わって 月を目指してみないか？
Are you interested in joining the sub crew for CES-62 and training for the moon...
エディ…｡
Eddie?
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)メールでも伝えたが
俺はもう…｡
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)実はな エディ｡➡
Like I said in my e-mail, I'm already—
Actually, Eddie...
そのメンバーの中に
ベティ･レインがいる｡
Betty Rain is one of the crew members.
Betty?
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)ベティ…彼女
復帰したのか？
She returned to NASA?
そうだ｡彼女の 宇宙への想いは
はかり知れん｡
Yes, her desire to go to space is tremendous.
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)まあ そう言われても
俺とベティは違う｡➡
Still, I'm not like Betty.
年を考えてくれよ｡俺はもう
充分やった｡やりきったよ｡
Consider my age.
I've done enough.
I'm satisfied.
ＩＳＳのノードスリーにある
換気ファンには➡
One of the fans in ISS Node 3 still has writing left there by an astronaut from the shuttle era.
シャトル時代の 飛行士の
落書きが残ってる｡➡
騒音の激しいズヴェズダ内では
エアロバイクの座席下に➡
The Zvezda module is so noisy, if you look under one of the aerobike seats, there's a box of earplugs.
耳栓が大量に入ったボックスが
隠してある｡知らなかったろ？
I bet you didn't know that.
俺は ＩＳＳに
計700日滞在したんだ｡
I spent a total of seven hundred days on the ISS.
ＩＳＳのことなら何でも知ってる｡
だが 月となれば話は別だ｡➡
I know everything there is to know about the station.
But the moon is different...
全くの別世界…イチから始める
気力はないよ｡
It's a completely different world.
I don't have the motivation to start from scratch.
よく こんなの弾けるな｡
No idea how you can play this...
そいつも ２０年以上やってる｡
今から 俺に➡
I've been playing it for over twenty years.
Asking me to go to the moon is like asking me to learn to play piano.
ピアノを始めろって言ってるような
もんだぞ｡月面に行けってのはな｡
それは 分かってるが…
ブライアンは 両方弾いたぞ｡
I understand that...
But Brian played both.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)なあ エディ｡これは
あんたの心の片隅に➡
Hey, Eddie...
Just keep this in the corner of your heart.
とどめていてくれりゃ
いいいんだが…｡
I want to hear you play the piano.
私は あんたの
ピアノが聴きたいんだ｡
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)お～！見ろよ 兄ちゃん！
｢宇宙でも壊れない｣だって｡
Look, Bro!
It says that they'll last in space!
Winter
これ すっげえ欲しいなぁ！
I really want one!
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)９０ドルか…｡
高いの？
Ninety dollars, huh?
Is that expensive?
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)高いね｡
Pretty expensive.
あ…じゃあさ サンタに
お願いしようよ｡
Brian Jay (Age 11)                                           Eddie Jay (Age 13)
In that case, I'll ask Santa to bring two for Christmas.
今度のクリスマス｡
僕と兄ちゃんの１個ずつ！
One for you and one for me.
そうだな じゃあ 兄ちゃんが
サンタに手紙出しとくよ｡
Good idea.
Then I'll write a letter to Santa.
やったっ！やった～！
あ でも こいつさ…｡➡
Yes! Awesome!
But do you really think they'd survive space?
ほんとに 宇宙空間 平気かな？
Wanna find out, Brian?
試してみるか？ブライアン｡
俺らが月に行った時
一緒に月面に並べようぜ これ｡
When we go to the moon,
we can put them on display.
あっ！…それ やりたい！
Count me in!
ブライアンおじさん！久しぶり！
Uncle Brian, I haven't seen you forever!
Hey, Tommy.
おう トミー｡恋してるかい？
Have you found true love?
(トミー)あんまり…勉強はしてる｡
No, I'm busy studying.
Is that so?
そうか｡大変だなあ 子供は｡
Must be hard being a kid...
なんだ 珍しいな｡どうした？
This is a surprise.
What's up?
ああ そろそろ こいつを
飾りたくなってな…｡➡
Yeah, I'm itching to take these up...
So I dug them out of the closet.
クローゼットの奥から
引っ張り出してきた｡
Well? Remember these?
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)どうだ？懐かしいだろ？
まだあったのか！ハハハッ！
You still had them?
You bet... Don't tell me you'd forgotten.
当然！忘れたなんて
言わねえでくれよな｡➡
そのエディ人形は渡しとく｡➡
I'll give you the Eddie figure.
While you wait to go to the moon, you can keep it wherever you want.
月行きが決まるまで
好きな場所に飾ってやってくれ｡➡
で 俺のこのブライアン人形は…｡
As for the Brian figure,
２年後のミッションで
月面に飾ってくる！
I'll be leaving it on the moon during the mission in two years.
その約束は覚えてるけどな…
わかってんだろ ブライアン｡
I remember the promise we made...
But it's already been decided, Brian.
俺も月には志願した｡
だが 選ばれたのは お前だけだ｡
I applied to go to the moon,
but only you were chosen.
フッ…あのメガネブルドッグが
わかってねぇだけだ｡
The bulldog with glasses doesn't understand.
まあ 今は無理でも➡
You may not have a chance now.
But once he retires, things could change.
奴が室長を退任する頃には
流れも変わってるだろう｡
You'll get your chance to go to the moon.
いつか 月に行くべき時は来る｡
I find it hard to believe.
《無理な話だ｡何年後かに
そんな日が来たとしても➡
Even if I eventually get a chance,
I'll already have retired by then.
その時はもう 俺は引退する頃だ》
現在
《今から月だなんて…
バカげてる》
It'd be stupid to begin training for the moon now.
(エディ)おいおい トミー｡
Hey, Tommy...
その格好 バンド用のじゃねえか｡
Aren't those clothes for your band?
学校へは
普通の服装で行く約束だろ｡
You promised to wear normal clothes for school.
今日 学校 マジ休みなんだよ｡
マジ開校記念日だし｡
We have today off...
It's Founder's Day for real.
年に何回開校してんだ
お前の大学は｡
How many times was your school founded in one year?
大丈夫よ｡今日のは本物｡
これからスタジオで練習だって｡
It's okay.
Today really is Founder's Day.
They'll be practicing in the studio today.
Hey, Dad... Look at the lyrics for our new song.
ねえ父さん 新曲の歌詞見てよ｡
あ ああ…できたか｡
Huh? Oh, you finished it already?
何？『血まみれの魂』
へえ…｡
Let's see.
"Blood-covered Soul"?
｢破滅の時が来た｡運命の苦痛に
天使たちは ひざまずき➡
"Apocalypse cometh.
Angels are brought to their knees by the pain fate deals.
I am eternally consumed by hatred.
私は永遠の憎悪に呪われる｣｡
｢血まみれの魂よ！
地獄を目指すのだ｣｡
Blood-covered soul, your destination is hell.
｢それはまるで 神のそれのような
あれのようだ｣｡
It is like the stuff of gods.
Blood-covered soul, your destination is hell."
｢血まみれの魂よ！
地獄を目指すのだ｣｡
なかなかいいんじゃねえか？
ワケわかんねえけど｡
ホント!?よっしゃ！
Not bad...
I didn't understand any of it, though.
Really? Great!
Except for the "blood-covered soul" part...
ただ この
｢血まみれの魂｣ってのがなあ…｡
｢血みどろの魂｣の方が
力強いんじゃねえか？
Wouldn't "blood-dripping soul" sound stronger?
｢血みどろの魂｣｡
"Blood-dripping soul"?
うぉ～っ！すげえよ 父さん！
マジ尊敬！
That's awesome, Dad!
You've earned my respect!
"Blood-dripping soul" is way better!
｢血みどろの魂｣の方が
断然いいよ！ヤベエよ!!
そうだろ｡
No kidding.
いってきま～す！
マジ リスペクト！
Peace out! Respect the man!
Is the whole following in his father's footsteps idea just a myth?
子は親の背中を見て育つってヤツ
あれ 迷信なのかね？
なんでアイツは 宇宙じゃなくて
地獄目指してんだ？
Why does he want to go to hell instead of space?
フフッ…そりゃ多分あなたが
当たり前のように宇宙に行って➡
That's probably because you make going to space and coming home look so ordinary.
当たり前のように
帰ってくるからじゃない？
普通に感じちゃってるのよ｡
It's too normal for him.
Space is part of everyday life. He's learned it from you.
宇宙は日常
ちゃんと背中見られてるわよ｡
宇宙が日常か｡そりゃあ地獄の方が
非日常でいいわな｡ハハッ｡
Space is part of everyday life?
I guess hell is much more exciting, then.
Say, hypothetically speaking,
なあ もし俺がこれからさ
｢月を目指す｣っつったら➡
if I were to tell you I was looking to go the moon, would that be ordinary?
そりゃ日常か？
(エディ)ハハハッ 冗談だよ｡
Just kidding.
｢血みどろの魂 地獄を目指す｣か…
Blood-dripping soul...
Destination is hell, huh?
回想 (ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)実はな エディ…➡
You see, Eddie...
During the CES-51 accident, Hibito happened across something.
ＣＥＳ-５１の事故の時➡
ヒビトが偶然
月面である物を発見したんだ｡
Yeah?
キャプテンのフレディが
それを写真におさめたが➡
Freddy, the captain, took pictures.
｢エディには 月で本物を
見てもらいたい｣という➡
But we didn't tell you because Hibito wanted you to see it for yourself on the moon.
ヒビトの心遣いがあってな
君には黙っていたんだ｡➡
I agree with Hibito,
私もヒビトの配慮には
大いに賛成だったが➡
but since you've decided not to go to the moon,
君 本人が月へは行かないと
決めたのであれば➡
もう見せてもいいだろうと
思ってな…｡➡
I might as well show it to you...
ここに その写真を置いておく｡
気が向いたら見てくれ｡
I'll leave the pictures here.
Take a look when you feel like it.
現在
What is it pictures of?
写真って…何の？
現在
月面で あんたを
待っているかのような…➡
Brian left you something that's waiting on the moon.
ブライアンの置き土産だ｡
現在
⦅いつか 月に行くべき時は来る⦆
You'll get your chance to go to the moon.
(エディ)もしもし エディ･Ｊだが｡
Hello, this is Eddie Jay.
Ah, what is it, Eddie?
[ｹｲﾀｲ](ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ああ どうした？エディ｡
ん～ まあ なんつ～か あれだ…➡
So, I guess...
My blood-dripping soul says that my destination is hell.
俺の血みどろの魂がさ
｢地獄を目指す｣っつってんだ｡
どういうことだ？
わかるように言ってくれ｡
What do you mean?
Can you make it easier for me?
だから 人生最後に
｢月を目指す｣っつってんの！
I'm saying...
that I'll spend what's left of my life to go to the moon.
The starlight illuminates my future, it's wow... truth
It's 3 AM, and I dream awake
With no idea of my future
only impatience consumes me
I have a thorn in my heart that won't allow me to lose to him
I'm walking a path of thorns I made for myself
But I won't forget the love I found
And I won't forget the ones close to me
I realized you cannot live your life alone
The starlight illuminates my future, and we are all shooting stars
My holy wishes turn all our sad lies into something better
Our orbits have gotten separated,
but I'm fine if you are close
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#94 Exciting Teamwork
As we continue training in the desert, I realize something.
＜砂漠での訓練が続く中
私は 気付いてしまった＞
＜このバラバラなクルーには
リーダーがいないんだ＞
This crew of misfits doesn't have a leader.
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Exciting Teamwork"
In that case, I'll be the leader!
＜こうなったら
自分がリーダーに！＞
Mr. Hibbit!
Yay!
(ﾋﾋﾞｯﾄ)イエーイ！よっ…｡
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
Super
Fire
Extinguisher
《これを使って消火すれば…》
I just have to use this to put out the fire.
Fire-suppression system in module 5 is malfunctioning.
第５モジュール 消火システム故障
爆発の恐れあり｡
Possibility of explosion.
うわ～っ！炎が強すぎて 消火器
じゃ全然ダメだ！どうすれば…｡
The fire's too strong for the fire extinguisher to put out.
What do I do?
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨｺﾞﾘﾗ)ゲホゲホ！どうするんだ
ヒビットが…ゲホゲホッ｡
Wh-What now? Hibbit's in trouble!
Stay calm, everyone.
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨﾄﾞｯｸﾞ)落ち着くんだ みんな｡
冷静に考えよう｡
Let's think of a way to put out the fire.
火を消すのに確実な方法は？
(ﾚｯｻｰﾘﾝﾀﾞ)消火システムが
故障している以上➡
The fire-suppression system doesn't work.
Module 5
火災を止めるためには
第５ﾓｼﾞｭｰﾙの扉を完全閉鎖して➡
So we'll need to seal off module 5, to cut off the oxygen and starve the flames.
燃えるために必要な酸素の供給を
止める必要があるわ｡
なんとか今 配線を修理した｡
I was able to fix the wiring.
第５モジュールへの酸素供給を
ストップする！
I'll cut off the oxygen flow to module 5.
Okay, do it.
よ～し頼む｡
聞こえるか？ヒビット！
Do you read me, Hibbit?
[TV]第５ﾓｼﾞｭｰﾙの扉を閉鎖するんだ｡
それで火は消える｡
わかった！
Seal off module 5.
That will kill the fire.
Got it!
Close Doors to Module 5
ダメだ！やってるけど
スイッチが反応しない…ううっ！
It won't work... I'm trying to close the doors but nothing's happening!
Module 5 danger level increased.
第５モジュール 危険レベルを
上げました｡爆発の可能性 大｡
High risk of explosion.
In that case, I'll have to close the doors with the emergency lever inside!
こうなったら 中にある非常用
開閉ﾚﾊﾞｰで閉じるしか方法はない！
[TV]やめろ ヒビット！そんなこと
したら お前が閉じ込められる!!
Don't do it, Hibbit!
You'll be trapped inside!
迷ってるヒマはない！
イエーイ！
There's no time to waste...
Yay!
イエーイ！こちらヒビット
消火完了！
[TV]やった～！
Yay!
This is Hibbit! The fire's out!
Danger
ううっ…うっ！
I'm suffocating.
苦しい…息が…できな…➡
Can't breathe...
イ…エー…イ…｡
Y-Yay...